INTRO

As a designer for the past decade, I have valued versatility above all else. I take pride in filling multiple roles on a given project, having the ability to work on identity, iconography, type, illustration, interface design, as well as front-end implementation.

CONTACT

570.212.9029

kyle.j.ruane@gmail.com

@kyleruane

EDUCATION

EXPERIENCE

Co-founder & Creative Director, Plain / 2012-Present

Creative duties for startup building a website-building platform called Barley, which included branding, marketing materials, pitch decks, app interface design, user experience, and transactional email design.

Bachelor of Arts, Commercial Art

Millersville University, Millersville (Lancaster) Pennsylvania

Freelance Designer & Creative Consultant / 2006-Present

Full service designer for hire. Many different types of projects have found their way across my desk, including but not limited to web design, application design, logos and corporate identities, illustration, and icon creation.

Principal & Lead Designer, Argyll Studios / 2010-2012

Management and design vision for a small creative firm with specializing in custom WordPress solutions.

Design Lead, Solid Cactus / 2007-2010

Design for over 100 eCommerce stores for various platforms including Yahoo! Small Business, eBay Prostores, Amazon Webstores, 1Shopping Cart and other custom solutions while working with developers and project managers in a team environment. Also worked on logos, information-based websites and a number of internal products.

Graphic Designer, Bailey Design & Advertising / 2005-2007

Worked directly with clients in designing various print materials and advertising/marketing campaigns, providing direction and creative solutions.

Art Director, Connections Magazine / 2005-2007

Responsible for ad design and magazine layout, as well as creative direction for Connections Magazine, a large format local arts and entertainment publication.

CLIENTS

Temple University
SFMOMA
MLS
Red Bull
Lifetime Television
Kennedy Space Center
Dave Mustaine
AC Moore
Everlast
Frigidaire
Burlington Coat Factory
Wells Fargo

Best Buy C-SPAN